Mss.Rec.184 Mss.Rec.184
American Philosophical Society
Recordings of Native American languages
Bulk, 1963-1973
1953, 1956, 1963, 1965, 1967-68, 1970-73
Mss.Rec.184
American Philosophical Society
30.0 Tape(s)
Audio recordings, primarily linguistic field recordings of Native American languges, removed from the James M. Crawford papers. The bulk of the recordings are in three areas: Alabama songs, stories, and fiddle music; Cocopa folklore, autobiographical stories, songs, and elicited words and sentences; Yuchi autobiographical stories, conversations, and elicitied word lists. Other material includes: Cherokee conversations; Chickasaw word and phrases lists; readings from a Chontal-Spanish dictionary; a Diegueño text; words lists and discussion regarding the Mobilian trade language (Yama); intermixed Mobilian, Choctaw, and Koasati word lists; Mohave songs, with explanations; a Navajo elicitation session, with interview and conversation; elicited Shoshoni expressions; Tolowa songs, Yavapai word lists and texts; and Yuki words and expressions. The small amount of non-Native American material in the collection generally consists of unidentified conversations, readings of English and Russian texts, and recordings of baby talk.
29 sound tape reels (41 hr., 59 min.): analog, 3 3/4 ips and 7 1/2 ips, half track and full track, mono; 3 in., 5 in., and 7 in. 1 cassette (15 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, 1/4 track, stereo.
Bullock, Matthew
Celestine, Phoebie
Cocopa, Mary
Couro, Ted
Crawford, James Mack, 1925-1989
Frank, Neddie
Frank, Seymour
Garcia, Florence
Gazzam, Warren
Hayes, Lillian
Hayes, Victor
Hoijer, Harry, 1904-1976
Huck, Charlie
Imataichi, David
Jackson, Gil
King, Laura
Langley, Arzelie
Langley, Rosaline
Lavan, Leonard
Lopez, Sam, Mrs.
Lopez, Sam
McCall, Mary
Melton, Robert
Miller, Hope
Miller, Sam
Miller, Wick R.
Poncho, Maggie
Pulte, William
Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
Thomas, Esther
Thomas, Frank
Thomas, Josephine
Thomas, Mary
Thomas, Vivian
Timms, Lester, Mrs.
Timms, Lester
Turner, Paul R., 1929-
Turner, Shirley
Underwood, Isaac
Wildcat, Nancy
Zárate, Clemente
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Elisabeth Crawford. (Acc. 1994-593r)
Biographical note
James M. Crawford was a linguist who mainly studied Native American languages, including Cocopa, Yuchi, and Mobilian trade language. He came to the field of linguistics halfway through his lifetime after pursuing a career in forestry in the West and Southwest. After receiving his PhD in 1966 from the University of California at Berkeley, he returned to his birthplace, Georgia, where he taught in the Department of Linguistics at the University of Georgia at Athens.
General note
Three recordings in this collection were recorded by people other than James Crawford. One tape of Chickasaw words and phrases was recorded by William Pulte and sent to Crawford. One tape of elicited Shoshoni sets was recorded by Wick Miller. One tape of Yuki words & expressions was recorded by Morrish Swadesh and Robert Melton.
Related Archival Materials
The James M. Crawford Papers contains extensive manuscript material relating to Crawford's recordings.
Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama Indians--Music; Alabama language; Birds--Songs and music; Cherokee language; Chickasaw language; Choctaw language; Chontal language--Dictionaries; Cocopa Indians--Domestic life; Cocopa Indians--Education; Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa Indians--Music; Cocopa Indians--Social life and customs; Cocopa language; Coyote (Legendary character)--Legends; Creation--Mythology; Fiddle music; Infants--Language; Koasati language; Kumiai language; Mobilian trade language; Mohave Indians--Music; Navajo Indians; Navajo language; Russian language--Texts; Shepherds--Folklore; Shoshoni language; Sound recordings; Tolowa Indians--Music; Tolowa language; Trail of Tears, 1838-1839; Yavapai Indians--Music; Yavapai language; Yuchi Indians; Yuchi Indians--Educiation; Yuchi Indians--History; Yuchi Indians--Social life and customs; Yuchi language; Yuki language
- Audio recordings
  - Alabama story, 1972; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:32; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Texas
  - How the witch was captured, 1972; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:27; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Texas; Witchcraft--Folklore
  - The hunter and the ghost, 1972; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:10; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Hunters--Folklore; Texas
  - The rescue of the sun, 1972; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:46:15; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Sun--Folklore; Texas
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:44; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:43; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:18; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:17; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 01-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:28; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama song, 1973-08; 01-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:26; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Music; Alabama language; Texas
  - Fiddle song, 1973-08; 01-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:30; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Music; Fiddle tunes; Texas
  - Fiddle dance song, 1973-08; 01-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:36; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 01-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:36; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 01-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:53; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama song, 1973-08; 01-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:44; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama song, 1973-08; 01-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:46; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama song, 1973-08; 01-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:07; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama song, 1973-08; 01-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:10; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama song, 1973-08; 01-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:02; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 01-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:45; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama word list, 1973-08; 01-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:20; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama language; Texas
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 01-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:17; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:02; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Why turtle shells are divided into squares, 1973; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:26; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Texas; Turtles--Folklore
  - Alabama story, 1973; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:21; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:01; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:20; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973; 02-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:15; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973; 02-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:51; Bettisse, Fulton; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - The creation of the world, 1973; 02-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:45; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Creation--Mythology; Texas
  - The Origin of the Alabama-Coushatta Indians, 1973; 02-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:12; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama Indians--History; Alabama language; Texas
  - The Origin of the Alabama-Coushatta Indians, 1973; 02-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:05; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - How the months and seasons were arranged, 1973; 02-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:46; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Seasons--Folklore; Texas
  - The great flood, 1973; 02-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:44; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Floods--Folklore; Texas
  - Why fire came to the Indians, 1973; 02-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:13; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Fire--Folklore; Texas
  - Why rabbit has big eyes and long ears, 1973; 02-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:09; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Rabbits--Folklore; Texas
  - The rabbit and the orphan [1 of 2], 1973; 02-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:43; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Orphans--Folklore; Rabbits--Folklore; Texas
  - The rabbit and the orphan [2 of 2], 1973; 02-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:33; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - How the state and the tribe were named, 1973; 02-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:16; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--History; Alabama language; Alabama--History; Texas
  - Why Eagle's spirit lives beneath the houses, 1973; 02-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:46; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Eagles--Folklore; Texas
  - The westward migration of the Alabamas, 1973; 02-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:03; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - The story of the crow, 1973; 02-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:07; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Crows--Folklore; Texas
  - The monster deer, 1973; 02-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:40; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Deer--Folklore; Texas
  - How the big lizard was killed, 1973; 02-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:09; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
    Alabama Indians--Folklore; Alabama language; Lizards--Folklore; Texas
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:23; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:53; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:59; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - A trip to the sky, 1973-08; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:54; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 03-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:22; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 03-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:49; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 03-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:26; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - The rabbit and the turkey's ??, 1973-08; 03-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:36; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 03-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:20; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Alabama story, 1973-08; 03-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:19; Bullock, Matthew; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; McCall, Mary
  - Baby talk, 1960s; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:15; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Scope and Contents note
    Language not identified on recording or documentation. May be Cocopa language.
    Children--Language; Infants--Language
  - Cherokee conversations, 1973-03-06; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:03; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Jackson, Gil; King, Laura
    Cherokee language; Conversation; North Carolina
  - Cherokee pairs, 1973-03-06; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:24; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Jackson, Gil; King, Laura
    Cherokee language; North Carolina
  - Chickasaw words and phrases, 1968-10; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:00; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Pulte, William; Underwood, Isaac
    Chickasaw language; Oklahoma
  - Chickasaw words and phrases, 1968-10; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:34; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Imataichi, David; Pulte, William
  - Chickasaw words and phrases, 1968-10; 06-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:22; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Imataichi, David; Pulte, William
  - Chickasaw words and phrases, 1968-10; 06-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:49; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Pulte, William; Timms, Lester, Mrs.; Timms, Lester
  - Reading of entries from Chontal to Spanish-English, Spanish to Chontal dictionary, 1971-09-02; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:36; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Turner, Paul R., 1929-; Turner, Shirley; Zárate, Clemente
    Readings of entries from Paul R. Turner and Shirley Turner's "Dictionary: Chontal to Spanish-English, Spanish to Chontal" (University of Arizona Press, 1971) The Chontal on the recording is Highland Chontal.
    Chontal language--Dictionaries--English; Chontal language--Dictionaries--Spanish; San Pablo Villa de Mitla (Mexico); Spanish language--Dictionaries--Chontal
  - Reading of entries from Chontal to Spanish-English, Spanish to Chontal dictionary, 1971-09-02; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:27; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Turner, Paul R., 1929-; Turner, Shirley; Zárate, Clemente
  - Cocopa song, 1963-03-06; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:24; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine
    Arizona; Cocopa Indians--Music; Cocopa language
  - Cocopa words, sentences, numbers, 1963-03-06; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:13; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine; Thomas, Mary
    Arizona; Cocopa language
  - Cocopa story about a fox (coyote), 1963-03-06; 08-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:39; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine; Thomas, Mary
    Story told in Cocopa by Josephine Thomas, followed by brief conversation. Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983).
    Arizona; Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Coyote (Legendary character)--Legends; Quails--Folklore
  - Cocopa conversation and song, 1963-03-06; 08-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:39; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine; Thomas, Mary
    Cocopa song, followed by conversation.
  - Cocopa words and sentences, 1963-03-06; 08-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:04; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine; Thomas, Mary
  - Cocopa words, 1963-03-06; 08-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:12; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Mary
  - Conversation and Cocopa kinship terms, words, and sentences, 1963-03-06; 08-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:41:25; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine; Thomas, Mary; Thomas, Vivian
    Arizona; Cocopa Indians--Kinship; Cocopa language
  - Conversation and Cocopa kinship terms, words, and sentences, 1963-03-06; 08-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:21; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine; Thomas, Mary; Thomas, Vivian
  - Josephine Thomas sings at Estrella Park (6 songs), 1963; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:44; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine; Thomas, Mary
    Cocopa Indians--Music; Cocopa language; Phoenix (Ariz.)
  - Cocopa words, 1963; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:03; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Mary
  - Diegueño words, 1963; 09-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:17; Couro, Ted; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Arizona; Kumiai language
  - Diegueño text (message to the Cocopas), 1963; 09-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:30; Couro, Ted; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Arizona; Cocopa Indians; Kumiai language
  - Conversation and Cocopa coyote story, 1963; 09-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:09; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Mary
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983).
  - Cocopa text, monologue, 1963; 09-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:38; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Mary
    Arizona; Cocopa Indians--Domestic life; Cocopa language
  - Cocopa text (a message to Mary), 1963-05; 09-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:48; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Hayes, Lillian
    Cocopa Indians--Social life and customs; Cocopa language; Invitations; Parties; Phoenix (Ariz.)
  - Cocopa text (a message to Mary), 1963-05; 09-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:51; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Hayes, Victor
  - Yavapai text (a message to the Cocopa) and song, 1963-05-22; 09-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:35; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Gazzam, Warren
    Arizona; Cocopa Indians; Yavapai Indians--Music; Yavapai language
  - Yavapai words, 1963; 09-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:43; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Gazzam, Warren
    Arizona; Yavapai language
  - Cocopa sentences, 1963-07-03; 09-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:06; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Hayes, Lillian
    Arizona; Cocopa language--Sentences
  - Cocopa sentences, 1963-07-03; 09-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:51; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Hayes, Lillian
  - Cocopa words, 1963-06-14; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:06; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa language; Cocopa language--Number; Phoenix (Ariz.)
  - Creator story, 1963-06-28; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:43; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa language; Cocopa mythology; Creation--Mythology; Phoenix (Ariz.)
  - Cocopa songs, 1963; 10-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:28; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
  - Cocopa conversation, 1965; 10-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:39; Cocopa, Mary; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Hope
  - A Visit to My Daughter and Grandchildren, 1965; 10-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:19; Cocopa, Mary; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Arizona; Cocopa language; Daughters; Grandchildren
  - Thoughts on the Last Day of Work with a Linguist, 1965; 10-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:46; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Hope
    Arizona; Cocopa language; Language and languages--Documentation; Linguists
  - When I Was Little, 1965; 10-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:33; Cocopa, Mary; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Arizona; Childhood; Cocopa language
  - Cocopa story, 1965; 10-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:36; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Arizona; Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language
  - Coyote-fox-lion story, 1963; 10-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:05; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Coyote (Legendary character)--Legends; Phoenix (Ariz.); Puma--Folklore
  - Coyote-blackbird-yapír story, 1963; 10-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:58; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Blackbirds--Folklore; Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Coyote (Legendary character)--Legends; Loggerhead shrike--Folklore; Phoenix (Ariz.)
  - Twins story (how to have babies), 1963; 10-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:14; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Phoenix (Ariz.); Twins--Folklore
  - Adventures of José, the Spanish Shepherd [1 of 2], 1963-06-28; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:03:44; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Phoenix (Ariz.); Shepherds--Folklore
  - Adventures of José, the Spanish Shepherd [2 of 2], 1963-06-28; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:49:25; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
  - Cocopa song, 1963-06-28; 11-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:50; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
  - Kayman story (alligator & coyote), 1967-06-13; 12-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:29; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Sam
    Alligators--Folklore; Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Coyote (Legendary character)--Legends; Yuma (Ariz.)
  - Špac kwamay, 1967; 12-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:45:33; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Sam
    "Špac kwamay" is a personage in the narrated story. Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983).
    Cannibalism--Folklore; Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Yuma (Ariz.)
  - Cocopa text ("sermon"), 1967-08-12; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:17; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Sam
    Cocopa Indians; Cocopa Indians--Education; Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Moral exhortation; Yuma (Ariz.)
  - Cocopa text ("mu u'kaa") [1 of 2], 1967-08-12; 13-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:39:15; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Sam
    Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Shepherds--Folklore; Yuma (Ariz.)
  - Cocopa text ("mu u'kaa") [2 of 2], 1967-08-12; 13-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:38; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Sam
  - The three presidents, 1967; 14-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:38:24; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Blindness--Folklore; Cocopa Indians--Economic conditions; Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Hunger--Folklore; Phoenix (Ariz.)
  - Coyote and his daughter, 1967; 14-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:50; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Coyote (Legendary character)--Legends; Phoenix (Ariz.)
  - The king's daughter, 1967; 14-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:17; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2996. See Related Recording.
    Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Kings and rulers--Folklore; Marriage customs and rites--Folklore; Phoenix (Ariz.)
  - Undertaker [1 of 3], 1967; 14-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:27; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa Indians--Folklore; Cocopa language; Devil--Folklore; Phoenix (Ariz.)
  - Undertaker [2 of 3], 1967; 14-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:50; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
  - Undertaker [3 of 3], 1967; 14-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:19; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
  - The three presidents, 1967; 15-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:38:19; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2994. See Related Recording.
  - Coyote and his daughter, 1967; 15-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:48; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2995. See Related Recording.
  - The king's daughter, 1967; 15-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:59; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
  - Undertaker [1 of 2], 1967; 15-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:47; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of same recording on APSdigrec_2997, APSdigrec_2998, and APSdigrec_2999. See Related Recording.
  - Undertaker [2 of 2], 1967; 15-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:21; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
  - Kayman, 1967-06-13; 15-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:27; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Sam